Guide to the Collection of New York University Surveys RG.3.4
New York University Archives
New York University Surveys
1932-1973
1932-1962
New York University Archives
New York University
RG.3.4
3 Linear Feet (12 boxes)
The reports in this collection span a forty-one year period, from 1932-1973, although the majority of the data is from 1930-1962. The surveys were commissioned and conducted by University administration, consultants commissioned by the University Council, and the Chancellor's Office. The survey material contains a range of data about the history of New York University, the history of higher education, the role of NYU as an urban university, and the relationship of the university with its city and region.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged chronologically within a single series.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains three linear feet of surveys and reports on the University. With the exception of the first box, which contains general surveys from 1958-1964, the folders and boxes are arranged chronologically, beginning in February 1930.
In addition to a number of surveys and reports, the collection also contains correspondence and memoranda, generated by the Chancellor's office and other administrative offices within the University.
Historical/Biographical Note
The surveys in this collection were conducted from 1930 through 1972 by the University administration or hired consultants under the direction and authorization of the University Council or the Chancellor's Office. Some of the survey materials originated in Chancellor Harry Woodburn Chase's office, while others were administered by Harold O. Voorhis' office or requested by non-university agencies.
The surveys contain statistical and descriptive data regarding the following subjects: the cost of higher education; student enrollment; geographic origin of students; divisional and course enrollment; course descriptions; faculty background and compensation; non-academic compensation; staff relationships with administration; comparisons of academic and non-academic compensation; the occupations and professions that attracted University graduates; finances, tuition, expenses and cost of buildings and facilities; use of space; and the development of NYU's public relations program.
The reports in this collection reflect the development of NYU's projected public image. The surveys confront major issues in higher education, such as the tension between the value of a classical education as opposed to vocational or pre-professional training. The reports trace innovations in the humanities, science and technical coursework, in the development of medical, dental, and nursing education and in the developmental relationship of the humanities to technical fields as a supportive intellectual area over a forty-one year period.
The University surveys also contain data related to the development of the technical and medical professions, and the professionalization of technical and medical occupations. There is also material related to the education of women, the history of non-industrial labor relations, and the comparative status of academic and non-academic occupations.
Access Restrictions
Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection.
Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted.
Provenance
This is a collection without provenance: the surveys were originally kept together in the files of Harold O. Voorhis, but were separated from the Voorhis files during relocation to the University Archives.
Washington Square (New York, N.Y.); Universities and Colleges -- Administration; Memorandums.; Correspondence.; Private universities and colleges.; Administrative reports.; Records surveys.; New York (N.Y.).; College administrators -- United States; Publications (documents); Universities and Colleges -- Business management; New York University. Libraries; Chase, Harry Woodburn, 1883-1955; New York University. Washington Square College of Arts and Science; Voorhis, Harold O.
- Series I: New York University Surveys, 1932-1973
  - Surveys: General, Feb 1958-Nov 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Medical School Survey and Development Plan, Feb 1930 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Survey of University Offices for the Committee on Educational and Financial Policy, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memorandum for the Special Committee on Educational and Financial Policy, Oct 1931 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Special Council Committee on Educational and Financial Policy, Nov 1930 Nov 1932 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Report of the Educational Survey of NYU: Vol. 1 part A: Introduction, University College, 1931-1932 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 1 part C: College of Engineering and the Graduate School, 1931-1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 1 part D: School of Education, 1931-1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 1 part E: School of Commerce, 1931-1932 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 1 part F: Washington Square College, Graduate School of Business Administration, School of Retailing, College of Fine Arts, College of Dentistry, Extension Division, 1931-1932 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 2 part 1: General Summary of Meetings of the Council Committee on Educational and Financial Policy with the Deans, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 2 part 2: Extracts from divisional reports, 1931-1932 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 3 part 1: Questionnaire and Statistical Data, 1931-1932 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Critique of survey, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Presentations, 1932-1933 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Report on Libraries, 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Report on Curriculum, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Works Survey, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Works Survey, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence between A.B. Hall, Chancellor Chase, Feb 1934 -May 1934 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence between Lotus D. Coffman, Chancellor Chase, Dec 1933-May 1935 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence between James R. Angell, Chancellor Chase, Jan 1934-May 1935 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence between Samuel P. Capen, Chancellor Chase, Sep 1933-May 1933 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence between Council Members, Chancellor Chase, Nov 1933-Nov 1934 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence between Deans, Administrative Officers, Chancellor Chase, 1933-1934 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Survey of Heights Colleges, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Survey of College of Dentistry, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Confidential Report of Provost's Office, Trends in Enrollment, Salaries, Ways and Means, Correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Nursing Education Survey, Correspondence, 1948-1950 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Booz, Allen and Hamilton Report: Survey of Top Management; Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - A Statement of Public Relations; Correspondence, Jan 1950-Mar 1951 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Higher Education Facilities; Correspondence, Jun 1950-Aug 1950 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - NYU Report of Facilities to U.S. Commissioner, Feb 1951 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - University Physician's Office Study, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Task Force Survey, Feb 1958-Oct 1958 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Task Force on Educational Program, Feb 1958-Oct 1958 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Task Force on Personnel Administration, Jan 1958-Jun 1958 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Task Force on Research Management, Feb 1958-Jun 1958 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Task Force on Space Utilization, Feb 1958-Nov 1958 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Task Force Miscellaneous, Feb 1958-Jul 1959 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Mission Report of University College, Sep 1962-Jun 1963 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Memoranda, Mar 1961-Jun 1963 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Memoranda, Mar 1962-Jun 1963 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Quarterly Report of the Board of Trustees, May 1968 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Progress Report on Increased Faculty and Student Participation in University Policy-Making - Revised, May 1968 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Commission on Undergraduate Education (Oliva Commission), Dec 1970-Dec 1973 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - University Without Walls Project Proposal, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Duplicate: Correspondence, Memoranda, Survey, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Duplicate: Memorandum for the Special Council Committee on Educational and Financial Policy, Oct 1931 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Duplicate: Minutes of Conferences of Deans and Other Officers Concerning Survey, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Duplicate: Works Survey, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Duplicate: Booz, Allen and Hamilton Report: Survey of Top Management; Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Duplicate: Progress Report: Commission on Undergraduate Education, Dec 1970 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Duplicate: Survey: Notes on the Function and Mission of University College of New York University, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)